The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（緑間(みどりま)）相変わらずだな 青峰(あおみね)
You haven't changed, Aomine.
Don't you understand?
分かっているのか？
You'll be playing against Kuroko in the championship league.
つまり 決勝リーグで
黒子(くろこ)と戦うということなのだよ
（青峰）なんか カン違いしてるぜ
You seem confused.
The past is irrelevant.
昔がどうでも 関係ねぇだろ
We're enemies now.
今は 敵だ
Well then, see ya.
（青峰）じゃあ 切るぜ
（緑間）ああ
Sure.
Midorin!
（さつき）ミドリーン！
落ち込んでるときにごめんねー！
Sorry to bother you while you're sad!
Cheer up!
（さつき）元気出してねー
（青峰）うるせーよ
Shut up!
（緑間）青峰！
Aomine...
Episode 14
You Look Just Like Him
（リコ）さ！ 帰ろっか！
Let's go home!
No, wait... Sorry...
（日向(ひゅうが)）いや… ちょっと…
ゴメン マジ待って
Seriously, wait...
We just played two games against kings.
（日向）２試合やってんだぞ！
しかも王者！
Oh, sorry.
（リコ）あ ゴメン
They're like zombies.
（リコ）ゾンビみたくなっとる！
We'll be fine after we rest for a few minutes, but Kagami...
オレらは
少し休めば大丈夫だけど—
火神(かがみ)がな… ムチャしたし
He pushed himself too hard.
I can't even stand, nevermind move.
（火神）動くどころか…
立てねえっス
But we can't stay here forever.
でも いつまでも
ここにいるわけにもいかないし
Let's go to the closest restaurant.
とりあえず どっか
一番近い店に入ろうか
Someone carry Kagami.
Seirin High
Dressing Room
火神君は 誰かおんぶしてって！
Let's decide with rock, paper, scissors then.
（日向）じゃあ ジャンケン
Rock, paper, scissors...
（一同）じゃーんけーん
（客）ああー うめぇ
（戸が開く音）
（リコ）すいませーん！
Excuse me!
Welcome.
（店員）いらっしゃーい！
ありゃ お客さん 多いね
There's so many of you.
Kuroko, you'll pay for this.
（火神）黒子 テメェ
覚えとけよ コラ！
（黒子）すみません 重かったんで
Sorry, you're too heavy.
（リコ）11人なんですけど…
（火神）お？
There's eleven of us.
I'm not sure we have enough seats.
（店員）ちょっと 席足りないかな
（笠松(かさまつ)）お
Kise and Kasamatsu!
（火神）黄瀬(きせ)と笠松！
（笠松）呼び捨てか オイ！
（黄瀬）ちーっす
Hey! No honorifics?
Hey.
（火神）ううむ
（黄瀬）ああ…
Why are we sitting together?
（黄瀬）なんで相席なんスか？
And Kagamicchi, why were you covered in mud?
そして火神っち
なんで ドロドロだったんスか？
I fell.
あぶれたんだよ
ドロはほっとけよ
Forget about it.
And don't call me Kagamicchi.
あと 火神“っち”って付けんな
If we don't eat, they'll burn.
（笠松）食わねーと コゲんぞ
（黄瀬）ああ ハイ
Oh, right.
Excuse me!
（高尾(たかお)）すんませーん
おっちゃん—
Sir, do you have two...
２人空いて… ん？
なんでオマエら ここに！
つか他は？
What are you doing here?
And where are the others?
（高尾）いやー 真(しん)ちゃんが
泣き崩れてる間に—
We lost the upperclassmen while Shin was crying.
先輩たちと はぐれちゃってー
（緑間）オイ！
Hey!
We figured we might as well get something to eat.
ついでにメシでも みたいな？
We're going somewhere else!
（緑間）店を変えるぞ
（高尾）あっ オイ
H-Hey!
Huh?
あれっ？
もしかして 海常(かいじょう)の笠松さん？
Are you Kaijo's Kasamatsu?
How did you know?
なんで 知ってんだ？
I saw you in Basketball Monthly!
（高尾）月(げつ)バスで見たんで！
You're a nationally famous strong point guard!
全国でも 好ポイントガードとして
有名人じゃないスか！
Oh, wow!
As someone who plays the same position,
I'd love to hear your stories!
同じポジションとして
話 聞きてーなぁ！
Do you mind if we join you?
あっ ちょっと
まざっていいっスか！？
ああ こっちの席で
話しましょーよー
Let's go talk over here.
That table is ridiculous!
あの席 パネェ！
Hey, hey!
ちょっとちょっと
超ワクワクするわね！？
Isn't this exciting?
You wanted this to happen, didn't you?
オマエ あれ狙ってたろ？
What? Of course not.
えー？ まっさかー
Why don't we order something?
とりあえず
何か 頼みませんか？
I'm hungry.
お腹 減りました
I'm already pretty full, so I'm fine with what we already have.
オレ もう
結構いっぱいだから—
Excuse me!
今 食べてる
もんじゃだけでいっスわ
Yes, sir.
I'm surprised you could eat that  ****.
よくそんな ＊＊＊の
ようなものが食えるのだよ
Could we get squid balls, pork balls, mixed balls,
（火神）イカ玉 ブタ玉
ミックス玉—
Why would you say that?
なんで そういうこと
言うっスか！？
octopus balls, and pork kimchi balls?
タコ玉 ブタキムチ玉
What sort of incantation is that?
You're ordering too much!
（緑間）頼みすぎなのだよ！
（黄瀬）何の呪文っスか それ！
It's all right.
大丈夫です
火神君 １人で食べますから
Kagami will eat all of it himself.
Is he really human?
（黄瀬）ホントに 人間っスか！？
I know losing sucks, but come on!
負けて悔しいのは
分かるっスけど—
ホラ 昨日の敵は なんとやらっス！
Yesterday's enemies are today's friends!
I just lost to him!
負かされたのは
ついさっきなのだよ！
むしろ オマエが
ヘラヘラ同席しているほうが—
If anything, I can't believe you have no problem sitting with them.
理解に苦しむのだよ
You already lost to them once.
一度負けた相手だろう
（黄瀬）そりゃあ！
Well that's because...
I'll get my revenge at the Inter-High, of course.
当然リベンジするっスよ
インターハイの舞台でね
I won't lose next time.
次は負けねぇっスよ
ハッ！ 望むとこだよ
Bring it on.
Kise, you've changed a little.
黄瀬 前と少し変わったな
（黄瀬）そースか？
Really?
Your eyes. They're strange.
（緑間）目が… 変なのだよ
（黄瀬）変！？
Strange?
It's a three!
（黄瀬）まぁ 黒子っちたちと
やってから—
Maybe it's because I've started practicing more
Hot!
Don't play with your food!
Sorry...
since we played against Kurokocchi.
前より
練習するようになったスかね
Are you stupid? Are you stupid?
And what do you think you're doing?
Also, lately I've been thinking...
あと最近思うのが 海常のみんなと
バスケするのが—
Kasamatsu, let me cook your food for you!
It's pretty fun playing basketball with the guys from Kaijo.
I can't eat anymore.
ちょっと 楽しいっス
（緑間）ふう…
It seems I was mistaken.
どうも カン違いだったようだ
やはり 変わってなどいない
You have not changed at all.
You have simply reverted to a state before our three consecutive championships.
戻っただけだ
三連覇する少し前にな
There.
Don't do anything crazy!
（笠松）オマエ ムチャすんなよ
（高尾）大丈夫っスよ
It'll be fine!
But...
けど あの頃はまだ
みんな そうだったじゃないですか
We were all like that back then.
How you change is up to you.
オマエらが どう変わろうが勝手だ
However, I am not playing basketball to have fun.
だが オレは 楽しい楽しくないで
バスケはしていないのだよ
You guys think too much.
オマエら マジ ゴチャゴチャ
考えすぎなんじゃねーの？
Of course we play basketball because it's fun.
楽しいからやってるに
決まってんだろ バスケ
What did you say?
何だと！
How dare you speak like you understand when you know nothing at all—
何も知らんくせに
知ったようなこと—
言わない… グッ
（緑間）ぐぬぬ…
とりあえず その話はあとだ
We can talk about that later.
Takao, come here.
高尾 ちょっと来い
（高尾）わりーわりー！
って ちょっ
Sorry, sorry.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
ゴメン ゴメン… ギャー！
（火神）うわぁ…
Kagami is right.
（黒子）火神君の言うとおりです
（火神）あん？
That's what I realized during today's games.
（黒子）
今日 試合をして思いました
If it was boring, we never would have gotten this good.
つまらなかったら
あんなに上手くなりません
Kagami, let me tell you one thing.
（緑間）火神
１つ忠告してやるのだよ
There are two members of the Generation of Miracles in Tokyo.
（緑間）
東京にいるキセキの世代は２人
Myself, and a man named Aomine Daiki.
オレと 青峰大輝(だいき)という男だ
You will face him in the championship league.
決勝リーグで当たるだろう
そして ヤツは—
He is the same type of player as you.
オマエと同種のプレーヤーだ
（火神）くっ
What?
はあ？ よく分かんねーけど
そいつも相当強(つえ)ぇんだろーな？
I don't really get it,
but he's pretty strong too, right?
He's strong.
強いです
But his style of basketball...
ただ あの人のバスケは
好きじゃないです
I don't like it.
（緑間）フン まぁ
せいぜい 頑張るのだよ
Well, do your best.
Midorima...
（黒子）緑間君
また やりましょう
Let's play again some time.
Of course we will.
（緑間）当たり前だ 次は勝つ
I will win the next game.
We don't have to play rock, paper, scissors for it today.
（高尾）今日は
じゃんけんなしでもいーぜ？
フン
But in exchange, your lucky item...
（高尾）そのかわり
オマエの そのラッキーアイテム…
（緑間）ああ 次からは
ぬからないのだよ
Don't worry.
I will not fail next time
because I will purchase an even larger Shigaraki.
今度は もっと大きい
信楽焼を買うのだから
The size isn't the issue!
（高尾）サイズの話じゃねえよ！
（店員）
ありがとうございましたぁ！
Thank you!
All right! Onto the championship league!
よし！ 次は 決勝リーグだ！
Yeah!
（一同）おう！
って… あれ？
Huh?
Where did Kuroko go?
黒子 どこ行った？
Excuse me...
（黒子）あの…
Huh? Where did you—
（日向）お どこに…
（黒子）拾いました
I found this...
（日向）はぁ？
（黒子）犬
dog.
A dog?
（一同）犬！？
Don't take him with you!
（日向）つか 拾うな
（伊月(いづき)）捨て犬かよ！
You're bothering the neighbors.
（リコ）ちょっとぉ
近所迷惑で… ん？
That's terrible!
（伊月）ひでーな
（小金井(こがねい)）どーすんだそれ
What are we going to do with that?
（リコ）キャー！！
このコ チョーかわいー！！
He's so fluffy! He's so cute!
Where did you come from? You're so cute!
どうちたんでちゅか？
Coach, calm down.
（日向）カントク
ちょっと落ち着け
Doesn't he look like someone?
なんか… 誰かに似てない？
（一同）うわぁー！
（日向）目！ 目！
The eyes! The eyes!
Oh, crap! He's already become attached!
（土田(つちだ)）ヤバイ
気がついたら 愛着が！
Okay! Your name will be Tetsuya Number 2!
（小金井）よーし オマエの名前は
テツヤ２号(にごう)だ！
名付けんな！
戻しづらくなるじゃねーか！
Don't name him!
It'll only make it harder to leave him!
（テツヤ２号）ハアハアハア
（伊月）まだ いんだな
捨てるなんてひどいヤツ
I can't believe people still abandon their dogs.
Hey, I've been wondering...
（リコ）ねえねえ
１つ 気になるんだけど…
What are you doing, Kagami?
何してんの？ 火神君
Uh, well...
いや その オレ
犬とかは マジでダメなんだよ です
I really can't handle dogs.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Having secured our position in the Inter-High championship league,
（リコ）インターハイ
決勝リーグに—
進出が決まった
私たちは—
難関だった実力テストも乗り越え
練習を再開した
we overcame our difficult exams and resumed practice.
However...
Damn it, I'm itching to play.
ちっきしょー
ウズウズすんなー
You have to wait until your legs heal!
（リコ）足が治るまでは
ガマンして
（小金井）ナイスパス！
Nice pass!
（テツヤ２号）ワン！
（火神）うわっ
Nice shot!
（伊月）ナイッシュー！
（テツヤ２号）ワン！
おおー！ ２号
オマエ バスケ分かってんのか
Number 2, you know how to play basketball?
（テツヤ２号）ワン！
（小金井）いけるクチだな オイ
You're quite the talker!
（火神）うわぁー！
（リコ）あれ？
Huh?
えぇー そんなにダメなの？
You really don't like them that much?
Yes.
（火神）ハイ
（黒子）火神君
（火神）ん？
Kagami...
（黒子）そんなこと言わずに…
（火神）同じ目で見んなー！
Don't say that.
Don't look at me with those eyes!
He's cute.
（黒子）カワイイですよ
（テツヤ２号）ワン！
Don't, Kuroko!
（火神）やめろ！ 黒子 テメェ
あとで マジ殺す！
I'll kill you later!
He's definitely doing it on purpose.
（一同）ぜってー ワザとだ
Make sure you pay more attention to stretching than usual.
（リコ）ストレッチは
いつも以上に入念にねー
まずは スクワット
We'll start with squats!
（一同）ハァ
（ホイッスル）
（リコ）はーい １分休憩！
Okay, take a one minute break.
（伊月）くー
キッツいなあ プール練
These pool exercises are tough.
Kuroko, don't sleep! Don't just float there!
（日向）黒子 寝んなぁ！
つか 浮くな！
（テツヤ２号）ハアハアハア
（ホイッスル）
（火神）うわぁ！
（テツヤ２号）ハアハアハア
What a cute dog.
（さつき）
かわいい わんちゃんですねー
ぶわぁ！ おおおおぉ！
（さつき）ウフッ
Momoi.
（黒子）桃井(ももい)さん
（小金井）知り合い！？
You know her?
Uh, who are you?
（リコ）えっと どちら様？
Um, how should I put this...
（さつき）えーと
何て言えばいいのかな
I'm Tetsu's girlfriend.
テツ君の彼女です 決勝リーグまで
待てなくて来ちゃいました
I couldn't wait for the championship league, so I came here.
Tetsu...
（リコ）テツ君？
（さつき）黒子テツヤ君
Kuroko Tetsuya.
What?!
You have a girlfriend?
（降旗(ふりはた)）オマエ 彼女いたの！？
No, she was my manager in middle school.
（黒子）違います 中学時代の
マネージャーだった人です
Teiko's...
（日向）帝光の…
（リコ）決勝リーグって
次の対戦校なの？
The championship league?
Are we up against her school next?
（さつき）あっ テツくーん！
久しぶり 会いたかったぁ
Tetsu!
It's good to see you again!
I missed you!
I can't breathe, Momoi.
（黒子）苦しいです 桃井さん
（小金井）なにがなんだか
分かんねーけど
I don't know what's going on!
I'm unbelievably jealous, Kuroko!
（伊月）うらやましすぎる 黒子！
Kuroko, you lucky bastard!
（降旗）いいなあ 黒子！
死ねばいいのに！
I hope you die!
（さつき）ウッフフフ
（小金井）ちょっ いやいや—
Wait, why Kuroko?
なんで黒子！？
He's dull and invisible and boring!
さえねーし 薄いし
パッとしねーし！
What? That's what's so good about him.
（さつき）え〜
そこがいいんですよ〜
But isn't the way he becomes a different person when he plays striking?
でも 試合になると—
別人みたく りりしくなるとことか
グッときません？ あと—
Besides...
He gave me a popsicle.
アイスくれたんです
What?
（男子生徒）これさぁ 新しい味
So, there's a new...
That must be nice.
（さつき）なんかいいな ああいう
みんなでアイス食べるとか…
Eating popsicles with everyone...
（黒子）あのー
（さつき）ん？
Excuse me.
I don't want this anymore, so you can have it.
（黒子）ボク もういらないんで
これあげます
What?
I can have it?
あげますって…
You're giving me your garbage?
ゴミくれるってどういうこと？
Don't you think that's mean?
てか ひどくない？
Winner
（花火の音）
（さつき）あああぁぁ！
ウフフッ
That's why I wanted to go to the same school as Tetsu.
だから ホントは
テツ君と同じ学校行きたかったの
けど… けど！
But, but...
（号泣）
（黒子）桃井さん—
Momoi, your voice echoes inside the pool,
プール内は響くんで
大声は控えてください
so please don't yell.
（一同）何だ この展開！
What's going on?
W-Who does she think she is?
なっ なんなのよ あの子！
Just because her boobs are a little big
and she's kind of cute,
そもそも ちょっと胸が大っきくて
かわいいぐらいで—
you guys are making too much of a fuss over her!
みんな あわてすぎよ もう！
Right, Hyuga?
（リコ）ねえ 日向君？
（日向）うん そうだね
Yeah, right.
Wait, Tetsu!
（さつき）待って テツくぅーん
テツ君てばぁ
Tetsu!
Don't try to sneak glances at her!
（殴る音）
（リコ）チラ見してんじゃねえよ！
（日向）ぐはっ！
（水音）
（日向）ぷはぁ
You'll kill Hyuga!
（さつき）日向さん
死んじゃいますよー
Huh? How do you know my name?
えっ なんで オレの名前を？
I know all of you.
知ってますよー
誠凛(せいりん)バスケ部キャプテンで
クラッチシューター 日向さん
Seirin basketball club captain and clutch shooter, Hyuga.
The eagle-eyed point guard, Izuki.
イーグルアイを持つ
ポイントガード 伊月さん
The silent and hard working hook shot artist, Mitobe.
無口な仕事人で
フックシューター 水戸部(みとべ)さん
The power forward with incredible jumping power, Kagami.
圧倒的なジャンプ力を持つ
パワーフォワード 火神君
Also Koganei and Tsuchida.
小金井さん 土田さん
What?
（小金井）あれっ？
（土田）そんだけ？
That's all?
Finally...
（さつき）そして—
The barely-B coach, Riko.
ギリギリＢのカントク
リコさん
（リコ）ギャー！！
ふ ふざけんなあ！
D-Don't be ridiculous!
What's her problem?
（リコ）なんなのよ こいつ〜！？
Momoi...
桃井さん
Did you really go to Aomine's school?
やっぱり 青峰君のとこ
行ったんですか
Yeah.
テツ君と一緒の学校に
行きたかったのは本当だよ
I really did want to go to your school.
けど あいつ ほっとくと
何しでかすか 分かんないからさ
But who knows what he'll do if I don't watch him?
He looks just like you.
この子 テツ君にそっくりだね
（テツヤ２号）ウー
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
He's so cute!
なーんか かわいすぎ！
I can't just sit around anymore.
（火神）そうそう
じっとしてらんねーよな！
The pain's mostly gone!
痛みだって もうほとんど…
くぅぅっ
Hey.
（青峰）よう
（火神）ん？
You're Kagami Taiga, right?
（青峰）火神大我(たいが) だろ？
Play me.
相手しろ 試してやるから
I'll test you.
What?
ああ？ 誰だ テメー
Who the hell are you?
I don't take kindly to guys who tell me to play them without even telling me their names.
名乗りもしねえで
相手しろとか 気に入らねーな
I'm not asking how you feel.
（青峰）オマエの気分とか
聞いてねーよ
If I tell you to play, you play.
やれっつったら やるんだよ
I guess I can at least tell you my name first.
ま 名前くらいは言ってやるよ
青峰大輝だ
It's Aomine Daiki.
Aomine?
（火神）青峰！？
I've heard about you,
（火神）名前は聞いてるぜ
けど そんな上から もの言われて
素直にハイなんて言うわけ…
but you can't expect me to just say yes when you talk down to me like—
（青峰）ハハハ オイ オイ！
だから 聞いてねーんだよ
Come on, now!
I said I'm not asking.
Shut up and play.
グダグダ言ってねーで やれ
誰も 勝負になるなんて
思ってねーよ
No one's expecting a real match.
I told you, I'm just testing you.
言ったろ “試してやる”って
I'm not looking for something that doesn't exist, like a stronger player than myself.
オレより強いヤツとか—
存在しねえもん
探してるわけじゃねーんだよ
I just want to know how much you can do to relieve my boredom.
オレの退屈を オマエがどれだけ
楽しませられるかってだけの話だ
From Kise to Midorima,
黄瀬といい 緑間といい—
“キセキの世代”ってのは
カンに障るヤツばっかだけど—
the Generation of Miracles is full of guys who piss me off.
But you're on another level.
テメーは そん中でも格別だな
I'll crush you.
ブッ倒してやるよ！
Congratulations on advancing to the championship league.
（さつき）
決勝リーグ進出 おめでと！
Momoi, aren't you going too?
（黒子）
桃井さんのところもですよね？
Huh? Did I already tell you?
（さつき）あれ？ 言ったっけ？
You just said you couldn't wait until the championship league.
（黒子）さっき決勝リーグまで
待てなくなってって—
言ってたじゃないですか
（さつき）あははは そうだっけ？
（黒子）はい
Did I?
Yes.
The next time we meet, we'll be on different benches.
だから 次会うときは
違うベンチだね
Yes.
はい
I watched a video of your game against Midorin.
（さつき）あと ビデオで
ミドリンとの試合見たよ
It was a great game.
すごい いい試合だったし
火神君て—
Kagami...
He plays just like he used to play.
彼 昔のあいつにそっくりだね
Yes...
（黒子）はい
（さつき）２人のプレー見てたら
思い出しちゃってさ
Watching you two play brought back memories.
Nice pass, Tetsu!
（青峰）しゃ！
ナイスパス！ テツ！
（紫原(むらさきばら)）黒ちんと峰ちん—
Kurochin, Minechin,
you guys are as infuriatingly in tune with each other as usual.
あいかわらず ムカつくくらい
息合ってるねー
Kurokocchi, I wish you'd pass to me sometimes!
（黄瀬）てか 黒子っち
こっちにも回してほしいっス！
Tell the captain.
（黒子）キャプテンに
言ってください
After watching that play,
（赤司(あかし)）今のプレーを見せられたら
当分は これが既定路線だな
we'll have to make this our standard course.
（青峰）ははっ
ホント なんでだろうな
I really don't get it.
Tetsu, we can't agree on anything else,
テツとは 他のことは
何も合わねーのに—
but we play basketball so well together.
バスケだけは かみ合うんだよな
I wonder why?
（黄瀬）
ほんと なんでっスかねー？
Kuroko is a shadow.
（緑間）黒子は 影なのだよ
（黄瀬）は？
What?
The stronger the light, the darker the shadow.
（緑間）
影は 光が強いほど濃くなる
In other words, working with a stronger player
つまり 強い選手と組むほど
黒子も力を発揮する
makes Kuroko's abilities even stronger.
It's not as though we are not in tune with Kuroko.
オレたちも別に 黒子と
息が合っていないわけではない
But Aomine is the strongest.
が やはり最強は 青峰だ
If he works best with Kuroko,
一番 黒子と
かみ合うということは—
ひときわ あいつの輝きが
強いということなのだろう
then that means he shines brighter than the rest of us.
Hey.
（今吉(いまよし)）ウィース
Hey!
（一同）ウィース！
Where's Aomine?
（今吉）あら？ 青峰は？
He went off somewhere.
（若松(わかまつ)）勝手にどっか行きました
てか またサボりっスよ
He's skipping practice again.
あぁ… まったく！
しょうがないやっちゃ
He's incorrigible.
Hey, Sakurai.
のー 桜井(さくらい)
Huh? Oh, yes! Sorry.
（桜井）えっ あっ はい！
（桜井）すいません
（今吉）は？
What?
I could've stopped him since I'm in his class,
自分 クラス一緒だから
止めたんですけど ダメで その…
but I couldn't, so I...
Oh, don't worry about...
（今吉）いや えーよ 別にそういう
（桜井）ホントすいません
I'm really sorry I'm alive.
（桜井）生きてて
（今吉）生きてて！？
You're sorry you're alive?
Sorry, sorry!
（桜井）すいません すいません！
自分とかもう羽虫っス！
I'm so weak!
Weak?
（今吉）羽虫？ いや もうええから
（桜井）すいません すいません
Sorry...
Sorry, sorry!
Enough already. It's actually a little annoying.
（今吉）むしろ 軽くウザいで
（桜井）ウザくて すいません！
Sorry! I'm sorry I'm annoying!
Sorry, sorry!
Also, Momoi isn't here either.
（若松）あと 桃井も
いないっスけど
（桜井）すいません！
すいません！
Yeah, don't worry about that either.
Sorry, sorry!
（今吉）ああ それもえーねん
（桜井）ホント
すいません！
むしろ それがあいつの仕事やん
That's her job.
I prefer the way Aomine used to play with you.
青峰君の テツ君と
一緒にやってた頃の—
プレーのほうが
好きだったんだけどな
He started playing basketball by himself.
バスケを
１人でするようになって—
Isolated from the team,
チーム内で孤立して—
I thought losing would change him.
それでも 試合に負ければ
変わってくれると思ってた
But he doesn't lose.
けど あいつは負けない
Even by himself, no one can stop him.
１人になっても
誰も止められないのよ
あっ ごめんねっ
Oh, sorry.
Conversations about the past always turn dark.
どーも 昔の話になると
暗くなっちゃって
Will he change?
（黒子）変わりますか
（さつき）え？
Huh?
If someone stops Aomine.
（黒子）青峰君を止めたら
What? But...
（さつき）えっ？ でも…
I know Aomine's strength, but...
（黒子）青峰君の強さは知ってます
けど—
ボク１人で
戦うわけじゃないですから
I won't be fighting him alone.
I promise I will beat Aomine.
約束します 青峰君に勝つと
This is ridiculous.
（青峰）話になんねーな
Did you really beat Midorima?
オマエ 本当に
緑間に勝ったのか？
Bastard...
（火神）テメェ！
（青峰）テツの目も
曇ったもんだぜ
Tetsu's judgment must be clouded.
You can't draw out his full potential.
オマエじゃ
あいつの力を すべて引き出せねぇ
あいつは影だ
He's a shadow.
The stronger the light, the darker the shadow.
影は 光が強いほど濃くなる
In other words,
つまり 輝き次第で
あいつは強くも弱くもなる
he becomes stronger or weaker depending on the strength of the light.
Your light is...
オマエの光は… 淡すぎる
too dim.
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
We're finally onto the championship league!
（小金井）いよいよ
決勝リーグだ！
Stay on the bench and don't get hurt.
（リコ）ベンチに突っ込んで
ケガしないこと
Oh, okay.
（小金井）お… おう
And don't miss all of your shots!
（リコ）どフリーで
シュート 何本も外さないこと！
And don't hit on our opponent's manager!
（リコ）敵のマネージャーに
デレデレしないこと！
Episode 15
Don't Make Me Laugh
Hey!
おいっ！